<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Smiling is Sexy]]></title>
  <link href="http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/"/>
  <updated>2013-03-15T03:48:59-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[David Aaron Fendley]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Be Not]]></title>
    <link href="http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/2013/yearn/"/>
    <updated>2013-03-15T03:05:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/2013/yearn</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Voices of an age of dilusion, we remain silent.
Poets in a realm of violence, we aspire to be broken.
Dreamers in a universe of possibility, we wish to be grounded.
Sanctity in a world lacking truth, we yearn for you.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mike Capps on Video Games as Art]]></title>
    <link href="http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/2012/mike-capps-on-video-games-as-art/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-05T11:04:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/2012/mike-capps-on-video-games-as-art</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>Video games are absolutely art. It&#8217;s the new expression, I think, of our times, where it combines music, cinematography, 3D art, everything together into one piece. — Mike Capps</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mike Capps Retires]]></title>
    <link href="http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/2012/mike-capps-retires/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-05T10:57:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/2012/mike-capps-retires</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Mike Capps of Epic Games is retiring:</p>

<blockquote><p>It’s hard to believe I’m writing these words, but here goes! After 10 crazy and wonderful years, I’m handing off my current presidential duties at Epic, and transitioning into an advisory role as well as remaining on the Epic board of directors.</p></blockquote>

<p>You will be greatly missed, Mike Capps. Godspeed.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA["Cosmopolis" @ the Art]]></title>
    <link href="http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/2012/cosmopolis-at-the-art/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-05T12:20:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/2012/cosmopolis-at-the-art</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just saw David Cronenberg&#8217;s, “Cosmopolis” at the Art theater. I am centered.</p>

<p>Combined with the inspirations offered by witnessing Philippe Petit in person three times this week, I am peaceful in being… Me… Perhaps, however I feel &#8220;in the moment&#8221; is a better choice of words. I am liberated.</p>

<p>Be weird.</p>

<p>While watching Cronenberg&#8217;s, “Cosmopolis”, I had a further centering moment. When Packard is walking up the stairs, gun in hand, towards Richard&#8217;s apartment, I was there. I was the director. I was David Cronenberg. I could see the ACs, the DP, the cinematographers — the entire crew. I felt what it would be to direct such a film.</p>

<p>I felt at home.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Steve Jobs on Design]]></title>
    <link href="http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/2012/steve-jobs-on-design/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-25T17:07:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/2012/steve-jobs-on-design</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>When you’re a carpenter making a beautiful chest of drawers, you’re not going to use a piece of plywood on the back, even though it faces the wall and nobody will ever see it. You’ll know it’s there, so you’re going to use a beautiful piece of wood on the back. For you to sleep well at night, the aesthetic, the quality, has to be carried all the way through. — Steve Jobs</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Technology &amp; Privacy]]></title>
    <link href="http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/2012/technology-and-privacy/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-15T06:20:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/2012/technology-and-privacy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://tracks.ranea.org/post/17612437174/two-contradictory-thoughts-about-apple-and-path">Watts Martin</a>,</p>

<blockquote><p>In a comment, John refers to the idea of the “allow access to the address book?” dialog box option as “security theater,” and it is—to the same degree the one for location services is. In both cases, it’s telling you something you probably should have known already (“what do you mean the Yelp app needs location services to figure out what businesses are around me?”), and none of us have any blessed idea what data any of those apps are sending back to their servers even with those dialog boxes.</p></blockquote>

<p>Good designers use dialogue boxes minimally, yet sometimes we are forced to implement &#8220;checkpoints&#8221; for reasons none other than passing the buck. &#8220;You chose to give us your information!&#8221;</p>

<p>This isn&#8217;t to say that there aren&#8217;t valid reasons for having these checkpoints, but as explained above, they don&#8217;t tell us what is being done with that information. The answer to this is developer responsibility. Developers need to create a bond of trust with their users by crafting solutions that take their user&#8217;s emotions and respect into account. They need to realize the threat of breaking this trust, understanding the risks of alienating their user base. This threat of abandonment, in turn, is the check-and-balance provided by the user.</p>

<p>Inundating the user with &#8220;policies&#8221; is not the answer.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Every Day Is Exactly the Same]]></title>
    <link href="http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/2011/every-day-is-exactly-the-same/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-27T18:08:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/2011/every-day-is-exactly-the-same</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Comfort Zones are a dangerous place to lie. They deceive, they thwart. They promise consistency and predictability at the cost of high risk and high reward. Life is painful. Thinking is painful. Existing is painful. Fortunately we have been equipped with adaptation, the ability to subvert pain through constant exposure. Pressure: They say it maketh a diamond.</p>

<p>We toil in the mines of data, seeking to extract a better version of ourselves; one we can sell at a higher price to the covetous and the void — one we can sell to ourselves. We are the living strata of the earth, and yet we wish nothing more than to be lifeless, inanimate objects of subjective worth. If to live is better than to be lifeless, then surely it is better to be more than ourselves, more than human. Such a thing should come at a high price. We value our time. We value our assets. We do not value ourselves. Were we to do so, we would appreciate high risk and high reward. Within our very spirits would begin a fundamental change rooted in becoming the very high price we seek.</p>

<p>Discipline, restraint, and personal responsibility are the pillars of Human 2.0. We can not continue to exist as a self-proclaimed intelligent species when our behavior is modeled after that of the virus. We aren&#8217;t even respectful enough to be parasites. We feast until we die.</p>

<p>TV, Internet, information. We feast in new forms as they emerge. Where we once left physical waste, we now leave delusion, aggression, and division. We are not good enough to merit the title, &#8220;virus&#8221;, for at least a virus has a purpose. In our current form, we have none. Perhaps we are the Earth&#8217;s punishment for its transgressions.</p>

<p>Some predict a great change to occur in 2012, proclaiming the end of the world; others see it as the end of our current form. These prophets of prediction are a dime a dozen. Be wary of the public prophet, for they desire only to serve their ego. Listen carefully to the silent. They speak in words that need not be heard.</p>

<p>Wake. Eat. Work. Sleep. Wake. Eat. Work. Sleep. Again. The pattern repeats itself. Every day is exactly the same for those of us in a sick-cycle carousel. Wake, in our comfortable beds. Eat, from our comfortable stoves. Work, in our comfortable offices. Sleep, in our comfortable beds. It matters not whether these environments are physically comfortable. If it is routine, it is a comfort. We write checks from our couches and pews for to help the needy with idle hands would require discomfort. We shop online for to deal with others would distress ourselves. We captivate our minds with the Gehennas of the Internet for to step outside would require embracing reality. Reality is not as we would make it, so we bury our noses in our phones.</p>

<p>The Devil smiles&#8230; And we are left none the wiser.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[eBay's TV iPad App]]></title>
    <link href="http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/2011/ebays-tv-ipad-app/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-22T10:54:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/2011/ebays-tv-ipad-app</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://techcrunch.com/2011/11/21/ebays-ipad-app-now-shows-shoppers-relevant-merchandise-for-what-they-are-watching-on-tv/?utm_source=sendgrid.com&amp;utm_medium=email&amp;utm_campaign=website">Leena Rao at TechCrunch</a>,</p>

<blockquote><p>Users tap “Watch with eBay” and type in their zip code, cable provider, channel and the program they are currently watching; and using show and event-specific key word searches, the app will surface relevant merchandise from the more than 200 million listings available on the eBay marketplace.</p></blockquote>

<p>Very interesting idea. While I find the idea of using an iPad while watching TV distracting, providing it&#8217;s a show I care about, it&#8217;s good to see eBay thinking outside of the box, transending mediums to promote its service through potentially useful features.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Skype 5]]></title>
    <link href="http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/2011/skype-5/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-17T12:38:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/2011/skype-5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Every time Skype releases an update for the Mac, a glimmer of hope wells up in me. Could this be the version in which we finally get back the wonderful Skype 2.x OS X interface?</p>

<p>Alas, disappointment dawns as not only are we greeted with the awful, I-would-fire-the-designers-in-a-heartbeat Skype 5 interface that, unfortunately, Windows users have had to endure for even longer than we Mac users, but the UI/UX has been made worse, cluttered with features that take away from the joy of making a simple, high-quality call over the Internet.</p>

<p>&#8220;Man-in-the-middleware&#8221; at its finest.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rest in Peace, Steven Paul Jobs]]></title>
    <link href="http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/2011/rest-in-peace-steven-paul-jobs/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-05T20:48:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/2011/rest-in-peace-steven-paul-jobs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/images/posts/Steve_Jobs.jpg"><img src="http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/images/posts/Steve_Jobs.jpg" alt="Steve Jobs" /></a></p>

<p>Rest in Peace, Steven Paul Jobs. You were an inspiration to many, myself included.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Siri]]></title>
    <link href="http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/2011/siri/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-05T20:44:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/2011/siri</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Why the name &#8220;Siri&#8221;? It&#8217;s the name of the company they bought. Here&#8217;s what I dig about the name, &#8220;Siri&#8221;, aside from the the voice technology, the icon is great: beautiful and reminiscent of Hal. Combined with the name, and the way it glows and levels as you speak, Siri feels like an actual entity.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Resolving "Expected Block to Return True Value"]]></title>
    <link href="http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/2011/resolving-expected-block-to-return-true-value/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-08T12:52:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/2011/resolving-expected-block-to-return-true-value</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ever have this error occur when working with tests in Ruby?</p>

<pre><code>Expected block to return true value
</code></pre>

<p>Not very descriptive is it? <a href="http://www.ruby-forum.com/topic/1580334">This post by Deryl Doucette</a> explains that there was a regression introduced to Ruby 1.9.2 between p136 and p188.</p>

<p>To resolve this, simply update your Ruby:</p>

<pre><code>rvm install ruby-1.9.2-head
</code></pre>

<p>Or for patched awesomeness:</p>

<pre><code>curl https://raw.github.com/gist/1008945/4edd1e1dcc1f0db52d4816843a9d1e6b60661122/ruby-1.9.2p290.patch &gt; /tmp/require-performance-fix.patch
rvm install ruby-1.9.2-p290 --patch /tmp/require-performance-fix.patch -n patched
</code></pre>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Best Ideas Have to Win]]></title>
    <link href="http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/2011/the-best-ideas-have-to-win/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-29T09:39:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/2011/the-best-ideas-have-to-win</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>If you want to hire great people and have them stay working for you, you have to let them make a lot of decisions and you have to, you have to be run by ideas, not hierarchy. The best ideas have to win, otherwise good people don&#8217;t stay.</p></blockquote>

<p>&#8220;<a href="http://thesmallwave.com/ideas-not-hierarchy-on-steve-jobs-supposedly">Ideas, Not Hierarchy: On Steve Jobs Supposedly Making All Apple Decisions</a>&#8221;, by Tom Reestman.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[HP's One-Year Plan]]></title>
    <link href="http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/2011/hps-one-year-plan/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-29T09:33:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/2011/hps-one-year-plan</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>Let&#8217;s say you were given a year to kill Hewlett-Packard. Here&#8217;s how you do it.</p></blockquote>

<p>&#8220;<a href="http://online.wsj.com/article/SB10001424053111904787404576535211589514334.html">H-P&#8217;s One-Year Plan</a>&#8221;, by Al Lewis.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[When We Decide]]></title>
    <link href="http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/2011/when-we-decide/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-28T11:24:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/2011/when-we-decide</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have an obsession with the past and future. I will daydream for hours about what will be, spending other hours on what once was. In some cases, these dreams lead to visions, imaginations of a hopeful future. Other times, reflections on the past only serve to provide guilt, stress, and shame.</p>

<p>We must embrace the present.</p>

<p>It is important to remove temptation from one’s life. To this end, I set iCal to purge events after 30 days and will occasionally purge my task lists. Why should I keep these things around? I rarely look back upon them, and when I do, it is often a vain attempt to feel a sense of accomplishment, to see what I&#8217;ve done and where I have spent my time.</p>

<p>To truly derive accuracy from such reflections, I would have to implement new behavioral patterns and requirements that demand consistency. This is just more overhead and cognitive load. I need less. I need as little as possible. Our systems should serve us; we should not serve them. Thus, time spent digging through my browser history to see how I have spent my day is time wasted.</p>

<p>The truth is, we know when we have been productive and when we have not. We feel it. It is in our cells. We bask in productivity. We wallow in waste. This is the only compass we need. Yet Resistance lies to us. It tells us that our intuition is not good enough. No! We need concrete data. We need more systems. We need more structure.</p>

<p>Recently I began keeping a log of when I would wake and sleep. This was designed to keep my average wake time at 5:30 AM. I did wake up at this time for a while but began to wane. Eventually, I tired of keeping this log and ceased to do so, despite the fact that these systems only work if one maintains them vigorously.</p>

<p>I began to reflect: Why do i struggle to maintain such systems? While any new pattern takes time to fully adopt, one should have firm reason for why the given system should exist in the first place. “Because we always have&#8230;”, “Because they say so&#8230;” are not good enough. In order to have acceptance, one must have understanding. I had forgotten why I should wake up this early in the first place. My sleep schedule had become a game, nothing more than points of data on a spreadsheet.</p>

<p>My reflections deepened.</p>

<p>I realized that the reason I had wanted to wake up early to begin with was for the personal benefits. There was nothing magical about the time 5:30 AM, but when I would awaken this early, I would feel more refreshed, greeting the sun, ready to face the day with more energy and productivity. Waking up later in the morning left me feeling as if I were catching up with the rest of the world. Much later — devastated. Once again I had motivation, true reason. I had a pure desire for structure, one not wrapped in red tape.</p>

<p>Reflections can give us appreciation for the past, but as a compass, they are only beneficial in brief and in change. The past is best captured not in numbers, events, and data, but in emotion. The writings of one’s feelings, the pictures of history, the scrapbooks of desires — these serve to remind us of days long ago, of impressions we had upon the existence of time and where those impressions will, or were meant to, take us. This is how we must reflect. Though our bodies may be machines, our spirits are not. This we must hold dear.</p>

<p>Structure is important, but it demands the right reasons in order to be embraced. We must be conscious of our time spent, choosing decisively, not simply reacting. The future depends upon the actions of the present. This future exists when we decide.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Light]]></title>
    <link href="http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/2011/light/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-25T10:49:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/2011/light</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>The most terrifying fact of the universe is not that it is hostile but that it is indifferent; but if we can come to terms with this indifference and accept the challenges of life within the boundaries of death — however mutable man may be able to make them — our existence as a species can have genuine meaning and fulfillment.</p>

<p>However vast the darkness, we must supply our own light.</p></blockquote>

<p>— Stanley Kubrick</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Legacy]]></title>
    <link href="http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/2011/legacy/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-24T19:24:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/2011/legacy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.apple.com/pr/library/2011/08/24Letter-from-Steve-Jobs.html">Steve Jobs has stepped down as CEO of Apple Inc.</a></p>

<p>It had been a dream of mine for some time to go to WWDC, to experience a keynote given by him.</p>

<p>First and foremost, I hope and pray that he is okay. One can not help but speculate as to the reasons for his departure.</p>

<p>At the same time, I am curiously looking forward to Cook&#8217;s reign at Apple, to see how he pulls the teams together and leads the company into the future. There is a lot of talent at Apple.</p>

<p>Finally, I am inspired. Steve Jobs is an incredible leader, innovator, and inspiration to his team, his co-workers, his fans, and many aspiring artists, technologists, and entrepreneurs around the world. I find myself challenged not to be him, but to take on the best of him — his standards, his vigor, his passion — so that I might be the same in my life, my work, my art.</p>

<p>Thank you for your legacy, Steve.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Migrating Old Rails Migrations to Timestamp Format]]></title>
    <link href="http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/2011/migrating-old-rails-migrations-to-timestamp-format/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-24T15:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/2011/migrating-old-rails-migrations-to-timestamp-format</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Enter your RAILS_ROOT/db/migrate directory and run this:</p>

<div><script src='https://gist.github.com/1178583.js?file='></script>
<noscript><pre><code>for file in `ls [0-9][0-9][0-9]_*`; do mv $file $(echo $file | sed &quot;s/[0-9][0-9][0-9]/$(date -u +%Y%m%d%H%M%\S)/&quot;); sleep 1; done</code></pre></noscript></div>


<p>Wait one second per file. Enjoy!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[There I Fixed It: TextMate]]></title>
    <link href="http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/2011/there-i-fixed-it-textmate/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-24T11:11:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/2011/there-i-fixed-it-textmate</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/images/posts/Vico_icon_as_TextMates.png"><img src="http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/images/posts/Vico_icon_as_TextMates_preview.png" alt="Vico icon as TextMate's" /></a></p>

<p>Because I love Vico but don&#8217;t like its icon.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First Pictures of Damage From the East Coast Quake]]></title>
    <link href="http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/2011/first-pictures-of-damage-from-the-east-coast-quake/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-23T13:30:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/2011/first-pictures-of-damage-from-the-east-coast-quake</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/images/posts/First_pictures_of_East_Coast_quake.png"><img src="http://Tricon.github.com/triconium/images/posts/First_pictures_of_East_Coast_quake_preview.png" alt="First pictures of East Coast quake" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
